Guide to the Henry Lowood Papers SC1187a SC1187
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Henry Lowood Papers
1980-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lowood, Henry
SC1187
7.5 Linear Feet
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Lowood, Henry; Lowood, Henry
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-076
  - Archival Resources at Stanford - 7th Summer School, UCBerkeley, 2000 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - GS 175 Lecture Material, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GS 300, 1991 Fall (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - GS 300, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History Wired, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - WS 147, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IHUM 58 - Technological Views of Utopia, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Human The Machine, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IHUM + SHL, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IHUM, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - IHUM, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - IHUM, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - IHUM, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - IHUM, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - IHUM, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - IHUM, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - IHUM, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - IHUM, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - IHUM Lectures - Misc., 2011 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - IHUM, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Knight Ridder / Knowhere, 2000 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SHL, 2007 Oct 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SIMS Class, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Symbolic Systems Forum Lecture - Stanford, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - History 285S - UC Berkeley - History of Physics Seminar (Heilbron), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Riedel-Kruse, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Carl Therrien, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Thomas Wyman -> Fernando Sanford, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - GS 338: HEL Copies - Exhibiting German Culture, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Exhibiting GDR Culture - GS 338, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Film Studies 203A - Consumer as Creator, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - War Front Turning Point Video Game, 1991-2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Aesthetics of Play - Bergen, 2005 October (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American in European Consciousness, 1991 June 5-9 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Book of Nature, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book of Nature, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Championship Gaming Series Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gameworld Exhibit - Centro de Arte y Creacion Industrial, 2007 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - From Gutenburg to Galaxy, 2005 Feb (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cortada Project, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Direct TV, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - EE Museum - Stephen Boyd, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - HTGG: Early Documents and Contacts, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - HTGG, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - IEEE - Annals of the History of Computing, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - IEEE Paper-Electronic Weapon Against Cancer, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Primer in the History of Computing - Williamsburg Conference, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Knowledge Management and Corporate History, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Machinima, 2004-2011 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Machinima Reader - MIT Press, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Greg Thompson - Mazewar, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Media-X, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Medieval Libraries Project, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - NEH-JISC Panel, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Perham Foundation, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - NDIIP/SL - PVW Proposal, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Machinima Guide (PVW), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - SDR/PVW, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Internet Archive, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - HPS, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - HPS Project, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - HPS III, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - HPS III Phase III - Grant Docs, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - GIS Day, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - HPS Grant I II, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Simulating History - HPS AFOSR, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Simulating History, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Map Warper, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Creating a Map for Point of Attack 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - HPS II Phase II HPS III Phase I, 2009-2011 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - User Needs Assessment Workshop, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - HPS - Las Vegas, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NDIIP, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Preserving Virtual Worlds Project, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - PVW, HPS Budgets, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - PVW - Proposal, documents, project, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - PVW II, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - PVW2 Planning for Proposal, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - PVW II - Grant Docs, 2008-2012 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - PVW F2F, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Second Life Talk SL to Archives 3.0, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Play Machinima Law, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Shall We Play a Game, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - SV Lecture S [Silicon Valley Lecture at Berkeley], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Silicon Valley Top 10 Events, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Silicon Valley - French telecommunication executives, 1999 September (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - SV USA - SF Chronicle 1980 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Silicon Base/MouseSite, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - SV - Other Projects, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Living History" Proposed Jane Chai, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Steeples of Silicon, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - SL IP Process, 2009 Sep (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Sloan Project, 40026 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "Speed Limits" (SHL), undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Stanford and the Silicon Valley 2006 version (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - StartUp Project, 36909 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - PVW 2, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Warcraft Proposal - Landmark Series, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Stanford 1885 Exhibit, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Virtual Reality, Encyclopedia Brittanica, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Trento, 33848 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Commission. International Commission int he History and Philosophy of Science, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Commission. International Commission int he History and Philosophy of Science, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commission Mailing List, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gavan McCarthy, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - History of Sci Tech in RLIN, 1990-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - HST + Procite, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - HST File, 35551 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - HST File, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CIMAM Are Games Art?, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - CIMAM, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Copenhagen Business School, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - DIGRA, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - EMC Portland-Game Preservation, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Utah--Frontiers of New Media, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - GDC, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - HSS, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - History y Science Society Computer Resources "Electronic Age" Committee COP, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Annals IEEE, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ipres, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Kyoto Games Archives Conference, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Primer in the Historty of Computing Background, 1968-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - RBMS Hardwork of software history, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - RLG HST File, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - SAA, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - SCA, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - SCA 2011 --Life 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1988-1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Shot Session Meeting, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Shot HSS, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Shot, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Shot, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Tech Museum of Innovation San Jose, 1996-2008 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - WCHSS May 2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Preservation of Microcomputing Software Symposium, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Legacy Meeting, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - National Software Archives Month, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - National Software Archives Readings, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-200
  - Cindy Ahuna - Games and art (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oral histories (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Media-X (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Press (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SHL [Stanford Humanities Lab] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - SUL - Digital collections (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - SUL - Media preservation (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1994 trip (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BitCurator workshop (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1995 Trip Germany (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1996 Trip Germany (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1992 Trip Germany (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Comp. Lit - Intro to DH [Digital Humanities] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Digital humanities seminar, 2012 Spring (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - German Studies 175/275, 1995 Spring (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - HP Memory Project (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - German Studies 175 lectures, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - German Studies 300, 1999 Spring (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - German Studies 300, 1996 Winter (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - German Studies 300, 1995 Winter (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - STS 144, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - German Studies 300, 1992 Fall (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - German Studies 300, 1994 Winter (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - German Studies 338: Exhibiting GDR culture, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Media and Message (THINK), 2014 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - IHUM lecture: humans and machines (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - IHUM lecture: humans and machines, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Thinking matters, 2013-2014 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - STS 144, 2008 Spring (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - History 285 Popular science for women UCB (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - SUL Preservation (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Art-Tech exhibit, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - SU seminar (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 73 Easting [conference], 1991 Aug 27-29 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - AIP [American Institute of Physics] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American journal of play (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - America's Army (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Asheron's Call (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - AMPAS Archives - NOIIPP (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Art History of Games, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Asheron's Call 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ASRC: Ampex John Leslie, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Aufklarung paper, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Born Digital Heritage, Melbourne, 2014 Jun (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Born Digital Cultural Heritage, Melbourne, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Callifornia Acad. Of sciences (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Charles Babbage Foundation (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chemical Heritage Foundation (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Charles Babbage Institute (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Charles Babbage Institute. Software Task Force (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chemical Heritage Foundation (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Connections Conference, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Computer Museum (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Digital preservation (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Electronics Museum (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Energy and Environment, SUL, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Film Librarians Conference, 2017 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - FDG, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - GAMASUTRA digest, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Game Developers Conference (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Game Studies - various, misc. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - HEVGA [Higher Education Video Games Alliance] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - High Tech Business Archives Group (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Socrates - History of Science file (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - History of Science (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hypermedia, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Internet Archive (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ITU + CBS, 2012 May (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - KTEH: Macon (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Military simulation (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Noyce (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Re-imagining the Archive, UCLA, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - History of Silicon Valley: articles, etc. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Silicon Valley (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Society for Cinema and Media Studies (SCMS) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Smithsonian (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Solvay Congress (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Tech Museum - San Jose, Ca (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Technology and culture (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Terman article for Garland (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Third person essay (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - UT Austin, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Timoshenko (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Update or Die Conference, Phi Center, Montreal, 2017 May (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Virtual reality (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - War + Games (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Web History Center (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Zone of Control, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 55)